Today in the podcast, I sat down with Matthew Lemurl and Mitch Machigan of Blockchain Co-Investors
in what has become a yearly recap and a predictions episode. In this podcast,
we discuss the top trends of 2025 and some key themes to track in 2026. I think you'll enjoy
this one, so without further ado, here's my conversation with Matthew and Mitch.
You should not read any opinion expressed by anyone on this podcast as a specific
inducement to make a particular investment or follow a particular strategy,
but only as an expression of their personal opinion. This podcast is for informational purposes only.
All right, Mitch and Matthew, welcome back. I feel like this is officially an annual tradition
now where we talk about what happened in the current year and some predictions for what's
ahead. So thanks for joining us today. Great to be here, Matt. As always, we love your show. Listen
to it every week. Very excited to be here. Thanks a lot, Matt. Well, Mitch, maybe I'll start with
you and maybe just kick it off for those who have not listened to previous episodes with you guys,
a quick background on the firm and a personal introduction, and then same thing for Matthew,
and then I'm just going to hop right into it. We've been on a few times, so I'll keep it a
little shorter than normal. Fifth era, we're a multi-strategy venture firm focused on innovative
technologies. So we're probably most well known for our blockchain fund-of-funds,
which is under the brand Blockchain Co-Investors. Through those funds, we've allocated to probably
almost 60 early-stage blockchain and crypto, early-stage venture firms, but we're also very
active growth and late-stage investors, and we actually recently closed our first AI-focused
fund-of-funds. So now we're an RIA with offices in San Francisco, New York, and London, and I
probably should add full disclosure is that we're investors in several Castle Islands funds, so
very happy clients of yours, as well as likely investors in some of the companies that might
come up through our fund-of-funds. We're investors in more than 1,200 portfolio companies and have
more than 50 direct portfolio holdings as well, so full disclosure there. For myself,
background was an investment banker for many years at Morgan Stanley in New York and London,
and joined just about five years ago to build out our direct investment arm of the business,
and I'm a partner based in London. Amazing. I'll kick it over to you, Matthew.
I won't add much. I'm based in California, spent most of my adult career in technology,
internet, fintech, blockchain, AI, and love it. Love working with entrepreneurs who are
changing the world in profound ways, and I do believe we're absolutely in the middle of a
remarkable time. We're digitalizing the world and the software developers we work with are the ones
really driving that change, and it's a privilege to work with them and to back them, and I know
Matt, you and Nick feel the same. Really exciting stuff. By the time this comes out,
I think you guys will have published this blog post where you looked at some of the big takeaways
from 2025, and then looked ahead for some of the key themes to watch next year. Maybe less of an
outright prediction podcast like we've done in the past, but Matthew, maybe I'll start with you
when you think about the last year looking back on 2025. Maybe highlight some of the things that
you would identify as just the big takeaways. I'll do a couple and then Mitch will do some too,
but for us, 2025 was a breakout year for blockchain and crypto, and the world changed
in some very fundamental ways and momentum built enormously. It's not that there aren't
concerns and issues too, which I know we'll get to, but we shouldn't underestimate the enormous
shift, and it's felt at very different levels. I'll give one example, and then maybe we can
zigzag back and forward a little bit as we cover off five important takeaways from last year,
but the first is fundamental growth. At the end of the day, technology amounts to nothing if we
don't have great products and services that lots of people want to use, and in almost every respect,
blockchain came of age this year, literally hundreds of millions are beginning to use these
technologies, opening digital wallets, using stablecoins, benefiting from the speed and the
ease of access and the low cost products that we're now bringing to market. Obviously, we'll
talk about some of the specific ones later, but we actually think, Matt, that we're at an inflection
point. The other way of talking about that is that our early pioneers, the people that we've
backed and worked with over the last decade, they're now being joined at least half the world's
population beginning to lean in. The early adopters are now coming online as well.
Definitely feels to me like the use case around just saving dollars is driving a ton of activity
in developing markets, and I know you guys see that in a portfolio company that we share in
Yellowcard in Africa. There's insatiable appetite for dollars, I guess, is my takeaway.
Yeah, I think that's right. I would just also add that there's so much infrastructure investment
that happened through firms like Castle Island or the 2018 to 2324 period that now doing a lot of
these things on blockchain rails is truly cheap or very simple. Things like launching your own
Layer 2 blockchain, which five years ago would have been really complicated. Well, now you have
blockchain as a service out of the box, and you're seeing, and we can talk about it later,
but a lot of big name brands, institutional firms take advantage of those infrastructure
rails that have been laid. That's absolutely right. In Mitch, the US picture, I would say,
changed a lot over 2025. I mean, that to me was just a seismic shift.
Look, I think for me, the single biggest thing this year, in our opinion, is the shift in regulatory
stance. And I think for whatever reason, the Biden administration took a very hawkish stance
towards blockchain, to say the least. I mean, you guys covered it ad nauseum on the podcast,
but following the election, the regulatory stance for the industry has just shifted in
material ways. And honestly, I think the three of us, if we were here three years ago, and we
were here today to say where we are today, we wouldn't believe it. And let me just take through
some of the things that happened this year, because I think it's such a long list that is
important just to step back and reflect at a time of the year like this. We really started with the
Bitcoin Reserve executive order that was in March, that basically directed the Treasury to hold and
not sell at C's BTC. That also led to the crypto task force led by the cryptos are David Sachs,
which started coordinating between the SEC and the CFTC. We got a new SEC chair, Platkins.
We have a nomination for a new CFTC chair, Michael Selig, a pro-crypto official, and that just
started this litany of dropped lawsuits. Again, you go back one year, the SEC was basically suing
everybody. So since this year, we had the Coinbase lawsuit dismissed. We had the Consensus MetaMass
lawsuit claims dropped. We had the Ripple Appeals lawsuit dropped. We had the Kraken lawsuit dropped.
We had Wells Notices withdrawn from Robinhood and Uniswap. And I know one very close to your
heart, Matt, we had the repeal of SAV 121. There we go. On the bingo card. The SEC formally repealed
that. And you probably have grief because you don't get to talk about it anymore. So many
obsessions of yours. You don't even forget that happened in May, it feels like years ago. And
that basically allowed institutions, banks to enter the space without having really punitive
capital requirements. And then I think the culmination of it all is the Genius Act passing.
And the Genius Act, for many of your viewers would know, but if they don't, that is essentially
the stablecoin legislation that creates the rules of the road to operate compliant
U.S.-based stablecoins. And that passed, I think, in July of this year. And we've seen tons of firms
come in. So just in terms of regulation, the difference a year could make could not be more
stark. If you go back two years again, you had Brian Armstrong flying to London, CEO of Coinbase,
considering moving Coinbase to London out of the U.S. Now you fast forward to today. I mean,
the U.S. is clearly without a doubt the center of the crypto blockchain universe again,
and capital is flowing, founders are coming in, and really the energy is back in the U.S.
So I think it could not have been more positive on that front this year.
I totally agree. I think that was very well said across all dimensions. It's great to see the bank
regulators becoming more welcoming of the industry. Certainly, Echo, what you're saying about founders
coming back to the U.S. and just new company formations, really picking up in the U.S. across
a lot of these categories. Also, in the U.S. market, I'd say, and maybe I'll kick it over you,
Matthew, to talk a little bit more about this, the institutionalization story here
has really accelerated, I think, largely because of some of this regulatory clarity.
That's right. This is the third big theme if you look back over 2025. And I think you can go back
a year or two earlier. If we went back 2022, 2023, we were being hammered every day in the press
by CEOs of banks and payment companies and asset managers who are basically doing the
blockbuster. We don't need this will amount to nothing. It's a waste of time and energy.
And in fact, it should be banned, and the entrepreneurs should be pushed offshore or put
into jail. And it was difficult for us as an industry to deal with that constant negative
sniping. We were saying at the time that we should, as an industry, expect it because
incumbents just can't stand up and say, our products are expensive, slow, not really fit
for purpose. They're never going to say that. They're always going to defend what they do today
whilst monitoring what's coming next. That's just good corporate strategy.
What's changed in 2025 is you'll find it very hard today to find a traditional finance CEO or
senior executive who's willing to say any of those things. In fact, they're all saying the other
side now. They're all saying, we're going to be upgrading our infrastructure. We're going to be
bringing new products and services to market. We are investing in people and capability in this
blockchain and digital asset space. And they'll have their own flavor of what that actually means.
So the payment companies Visa Mastercard are beginning to experiment, make a few acquisitions,
roll out a few things. The big banks are now actively talking about having digital asset
custody and stablecoin rails alongside their other payment rails. The asset managers led by Larry
Fink and BlackRock are now talking about, we make Bitcoin ETFs available to our customers and we're
beginning to experiment with real-world asset tokenization. So this is actually an enormous
180-degree shift that occurred this year. For our industry, we have mixed feelings about it because
you and we back the disruptive companies that are already bringing those products and services to
market. And to some extent, traditional players coming into our space is competition. And to some
extent, they may threaten or modify or change the things that we would have liked to have seen
done. And just this week, the DTCC is now talking about real-world asset tokenization of all of
the products they support. We know, obviously, they'll try and influence legislation so that
they become the only people in America that have the right to set the standards and to
digitalize those real-world assets. So large, well-funded incumbents coming into a space is
always a double-edged sword. They accelerate adoption. They can actually help clear away
roadblocks. But they're also going to try and tip the playing field in their favor. And yet again,
they can also be a merger and acquisition roll-up option for some of the portfolio companies we
backed. So there's a variety of dimensions to this. But 2025 was a year when traditional finance
finally took blockchain and crypto seriously. But for the industry, it's not all good news.
It's going to be really interesting in 2026 around tokenization and just the market structure
clarity. So wouldn't be surprised if a year from now, we're also talking about the institutionalization
of just broader digital assets, real-world assets coming on chain. So I think it was a great call
out just in the acceleration we saw this year. Another thing we saw this year was equity really
took center stage. And maybe I'll shift it over to you, Mitch, around just what's happening in the
equity-focused market here, particularly on the venture side. Yeah. And I think this is our fourth
look back on the year is equity taking center stage. And I think we can definitely call 2025
actually the year of crypto equity. So really until now the industry had only one marquee equity
exit and that's Coinbase. Now, obviously I'm generalizing, but I think that's really the only big
one we could speak to. Prior to this year, the lion's share of venture returns were almost
exclusively driven by the token side. And as probably the most active early stage VC investor in
the space in terms of allocating actual VC funds, we have a really interesting perspective here.
So when we look at our own fund of funds, which again backs about 60 early stage firms,
our invested capital has historically been split roughly 6040 between equity and token. So slightly
more equity than token. But in terms of returns, these have overwhelmingly been token weighted.
So you had early token listings and the equity markets were essentially shut to our industry.
2025, this is the year that that dynamic finally started to rebalance. And I think that starts
with what we can call the class of the 25 IPO rush due to this regulatory thought. And the marquee
IPO of the year is probably the Circle IPO, which really was this firing gun on IPOs in the space.
But there were many others. We had Gemini, bullish, eToro figure recently announced the
securitized DSPAC with Cantre equity partners too. And then we have a number of firms filing
confidentially or publicly with the SEC, including Grayscale, Kraken, BitGo. So
basically we know that the equity markets have opened for our space after a long drought,
basically since the Coinbase direct listing. M&A also picked up, which helps the equity side.
And we had Stripe by Bridge, that deal closed this year. Robinhood bought Bitstamp, that deal
closed this year. Coinbase bought Derabit, that deal closed this year. There's a number of others
we could probably mention here. So also providing exits in terms of the equity side of the equation.
And then the last thing just to note, which we probably will talk about perhaps from a negative
perspective in terms of 2026, but we saw the enormous activity around debts or digital asset
treasuries. And these are effectively your strategy, micro strategy copycats that amass
one or more assets, whether it's Bitcoin, Ethereum, Solana, or long tail assets.
And whatever you think about these, I think it's just very interesting to step back and say actually
the most interesting thing about tokens or really the most capital in terms of tokens on the year
was around an equity wrapper. So even where the capital was flowing in terms of the token market,
it came through equities. So I think this is the year that equity came back to our space.
And a lot of venture funds that had stuck to their guns and continued to allocate to equity and
committed to equity, well, they were rewarded this year after a long wait.
A lot of what you're saying ties back to the regulatory environment. So if you look at the
banks, the broker-dealers, the payment service providers, why would you build out any of this
infrastructure if you effectively felt like crypto and digital assets were more or less
illegal in the United States? And now you find a lot of those firms just off sides in terms of
their product offerings. So not surprising that you're seeing a flurry of M&A to your point.
And if you remember, actually Circle and Etoro, well, they tried to go public in 2020, 2021,
and the SEC effectively stalled them out, just continued running them through the comment period.
So those deals could never close. So you had this long period where
the public route was a very difficult, if not impossible, route for the space.
So because of that, a lot of the exits, a lot of the energy had shifted to the token market.
So we're kind of having a homecoming now to the equity markets.
Matthew, how do you think about the market overall in terms of, do you see any froth reemerging?
So you and Castle Island and Nick and ourselves, we're long-term venture capitalists. So we invest
today in things that we think are going to change the world a few years out. And we don't really
care about the ups and downs of the market day today, where it impacts us is, as Mitch just
described, the IPA window can open and close, capital can be more or less available, and mergers
and acquisitions can be happening every day or not at all. So there are things that impact us as
venture capitalists, but we're investing for the long term. The traders, conversely,
they're very narrative driven. They're worrying today, will this stop go up today or tomorrow or
next week? And they have a very short-term view. And that does create issues, particularly around
the public liquid traded tokens, which are created by our industry, but are actually behaving in as
public market assets. There's a lot of capital that is able to move very quickly if there's an
expectation of a short-term change in the value of a publicly traded asset. And we've seen that
this year. So 2025 was a year in which Wall Street became comfortable deploying very large amounts
of capital into the products and services coming out of our industry. And that begins, obviously,
with Bitcoin and Solana and Ethereum. But it also included, as Mitch already mentioned, the DATS,
and to some extent, late stage rounds for the leading blockchain unicorn. So a lot of cash came
fast towards our industry and valuations as a result got impacted. And there is always a risk
that that can reverse. Capital can suddenly get less interested in a sector and flow out. And we
do see that happen year after year in VC. So early stage valuations typically don't go up that much,
1x, 2x, 1x, 2x. Mid-stage valuations can get a little bit more volatile, but it's in the late
stage, the pre-IPO stage, where we see enormous boom and bust cycles. And that's what tends to get
into the media. So the dot-com boom was very much a late stage-driven issue. So 2025, we do have
concerns. As we finish the year, I think that the weight of capital and some of the valuations
definitely began to look elevated, let's say, that way. And by the time you look at AI, I think
there's a very serious concern that the trillions of dollars going into the AI sector could actually
look a little bit like a bubble later on in 2026. We'll talk about that when we talk about 2026 in
a moment. So we do have concerns about as early stage venture capitalists every day, what we're
waking up doing is backing the entrepreneurs who are over a 5 to 10-year time frame are really
going to deliver value. And evaluation isn't the topmost question we're asking in those types of
investments. It's funny. In crypto, we have a tendency to just speedrun cycles. It felt like
earlier in the year, these digital asset treasury companies were the hottest thing around, but it
didn't take long for a lot of them to trade at discounts. So the frothiness in that part of the
market specifically seems to have come and gone just within the calendar year.
Yeah, I see that too. And the issues sometimes take a moment for people to get their heads around.
So capital can flow faster than the analysis, if you see what I'm saying. So in AI, as an example,
all of a sudden this year, people are allocating hundreds of billions of dollars to build massive
data centers all across America. But we haven't quite answered the question, what will be the
state of computing power in five years' time and will we actually need large data centers?
It's just an example. So capital sometimes flows against the theme faster than people have their
heads around the next 5 to 10-year perspective. And obviously, today's valuations are driven by
terminal values that do require you to have a long-term view. So it's pretty interesting
to watch Wall Street, but we don't participate as traders. We're long-term venture investors.
That makes a ton of sense. Well, maybe shifting gears a little bit and talking about what's ahead,
this is always the most fun part of the podcast, just trying to predict the future a little bit
here. So maybe I'll start with you, Matthew. Maybe highlight some themes that you're watching
for 2026. What do you think we'll be talking about? So the irony is the five things we just
talked about, fundamental growth, regulatory change, institutionalization of crypto,
equity-taking center stage, and the risk that markets may have become over-invested.
It's going to sound very similar because when we look ahead to 2026, we think a lot of these trends
are going to take years and years to play out. So the most important thing I think we're going to
see in 2026 is actually a continuation of fundamental growth and the adoption of these
technologies. So it's a repeat of 25. On our side, we've been tracking digital wallets for
a long time now. No one knows exactly how many there are, but let's just say that there's 500
million today. That means that less than five or six percent of the people in the world actually
have a digital wallet. So it's very, very early days. We think the curve of digital wallet openings
is about to get very, very steep. We think that there'll probably be two or three billion new
digital wallets opened in the next three to five years. So that's four or six times as many as our
industry was able to open up over the last 12 or 13 years. So this is a real steepening of fundamental
growth. And those wallets now have more products and services to utilize. So when we all opened our
first digital wallet, there were very few things you could put in it, and Bitcoin was the primary one.
Today, there's a breadth of products, not just crypto products, but traditional financial
products in tokenized wrappers and digitalized gold or other things that if you're interested in
having those exposures, you can just stay in a digital wallet and buy and sell and move around.
You don't even have to go off-platform, and you don't really have to deal with the fiat world
anymore. And I think that notion will also be another thing we'll see in 2026. So more digital
wallets, more products in them, but also the major players, the Coinbase, Robinhoods, the
Krakens, the Upholds, they'll all be trying to become financial supermarkets, and they'll be
bringing in whichever product categories they already have. They'll be adding others. And I
think by the end of 2026, we'll be looking a lot more like Alipay or WePay, where we have a real
breadth of financial products within any given digital wallet one click away. And I think that
that is something to really watch because this adoption curve is getting steep right now.
Yeah. I mean, there's so many vectors for growth there on the wallet side. You think about stable
coins, that's a huge vector. You're going to have more international payments. You're going to have
more dollar savings. Then you have the tokenization story. Then you just have efforts of centralized
companies like Stripe that are launching their own player one networks. And you wonder how much
that two to three billion would just be Stripe pushing forward wallet infrastructure. So it
feels like there's a lot of different ways to get to that two to three billion number.
Agreed. And big players now are going to try and drive that adoption curve up as well. So
Coinbase and Kraken and so on are fantastic, but their marketing muscle and the number of
current customers is only a fraction of the traditional industry. So as we begin to see
major players, major banks, major asset managers also open up digital wallets, they'll start pounding
the drum around, this is ready for prime time. You really need to have one of these. And I do think
that use curve will get very, very steep. Who's going to win and who's going to lose is a bigger
question. Personally, I think it will be whoever has the easiest, most accessible,
broadest product offering at the lowest possible cost is where the digital natives will go.
And I'm not sure that will be incumbents. I personally think that we're going to see,
it's sort of like Sears should have been Amazon, but it wasn't. JP Morgan should have been the
mobile digital wallet financial service provided of the future, but I don't think it will be.
It's hard to cannibalize your own business and it's hard to
move fast in bigger organizations. So I think that's exactly right.
Mitch, how are you thinking about tokenization and stablecoins as we move into the second
prediction here? So I think our prediction here, and it's very related to what we're just talking
about, is that tokenization and stablecoins continue to eat the financial stack. And the
fifth era thesis here is that all financial activity may ultimately settle on blockchains.
And that is a tokenization and stablecoin led story. And I think the big picture on this point
is that we're in the midst of a sort of great convergence. From a high level perspective,
we have this accelerating convergence of what you may have called FinTech or tech-enabled finance
and crypto. So this year, we saw traditional financial giants, and you guys already mentioned
some of them, but the likes of Robinhood and Revolut, well, they got aggressively involved
in on-chain infrastructure. On the other side, we have crypto-native firms like Coinbase and Kraken
and full disclosure were fairly large holders of Kraken, expanding into traditional financial
products by offering stocks and derivatives. So we're seeing this convergence where you may not
even know that you're using crypto products by using one of these firms. And again, the two use
cases driving this are tokenization and stablecoins, which we see as the backbone of this new financial
infrastructure. And as Matthew alluded here, really distribution is king. So you're Robinhood,
you're selling the video stocks to millions of American retail investors. Well, now you can
just move into crypto and offer on-chain products. So it actually makes a lot of sense. But outside
of those firms, PayPal is getting into the space. You guys mentioned JP Morgan, despite what Jamie
Diamond says, they launched JPMD, the deposit token, Visa is doing back in settlements on
stablecoins, Robinhood has actually announced its own chain, Stripe announced the chain.
So in terms of growth and really hitting that prediction from number one about a growing number
of users, you can start to see how we're going to have developed world-led growth through these
traditional and large traditional fintech firms, really pushing that again to a point where you
may be making a payment to a vendor with Visa and somewhere somehow there's a blockchain
transaction happening and you don't even need to know because it's been abstracted away.
And that's probably what it looks like in the US market to start. I would say you don't even need
to know that you're using a stablecoin. It's just that your dollars can move on the nights and the
weekends outside of bank hours. That's exactly right. And if you go back to previous
theses we had, we always saw this as a developing world story first in terms of direct consumer
adoption just because the payment systems are so archaic and you have high inflation environments.
So the salience of new crypto networks is very high. In the developed world, we have Apple Pay,
we have these things. So we've always seen it as an institutionally led adoption curve here.
And I think we're really starting to see that fruition. And then look, the last two things
here I'll say is, you sort of brushed on it earlier, but I just want to double click,
it shouldn't go unnoticed that a DTCC this month got the SEC no action letter. So again,
you can start to see that the real backbone infrastructure tubes of our financial system
is coming into this space. And you might start to see things like collateral management, move on
tokenized rails. There's a lot of really interesting things DTCC can do. And then also,
I think you should just listen to what the SEC chair is saying. I think our prediction here is
exactly what Paul Atkins said about two weeks ago when he basically said the entire US financial
system could shift to tokenization just within a few years. So for us, that's the direction this
is heading. This is the thesis our firm was founded on. And this is the topic we think is
going to keep coming up year over year. Atkins has just been such a breath of fresh air. I feel
like if one of us had made that statement a couple of years ago, people would have called us crazy.
And now you have the head of the SEC asserting that tokenization is going to impact the whole
financial system. And he's not wrong. It's just crazy to hear it. Matthew, how are you thinking
about the public markets in 26? So it's interesting. We just talked about 2025 as a year in which the
capital markets embraced the industry. And Mitch went over some of the very exciting things that
are going on with such a large number of blockchain companies in the process of going
public. The DATs obviously getting stood up and a lot of capital flowing. We shouldn't assume it
2026 will be like that the whole year long, because if you actually look over the last 20,
30 years, the IPO window is a cyclical thing. The typical IPO window is open for roughly a year.
And then oftentimes it closes for a year. After the great financial crisis, it was more like a
two year close. After the dot com crash, it was more like 2.5 years where very few IPOs were done.
And obviously under the Biden administration, there was a couple of years in there where
essentially no technology IPOs occurred. So just to give you a sense, just realistically,
if the IPO window has been open now for nearly a year, it's a fairly good probability that it
will close down sometime in 2026 for some reason. So that has an important knock on implication for
industry, because we've got an awful lot of blockchain companies trying to go public right
now. My hope is a lot of them will get out in the first six months of the year. But I think that they
and their boards should all have plan B penciled up already. And plan B is almost certainly a
DSPAC merger, because DSPAC mergers go on all the time. They don't come and go and open and close
in the same way that the IPO environment does. Now we've obviously got key players in our industry,
Tether being an example, who are now exploring completely different ways of going public in
the possibility of a tokenized Tether share being made available globally. I think that would be
very exciting to see. Direct listings do occasionally occur fairly rarely, but you never know. And then
there's a knock on implication of everything I just said for the M&A market. So we are beginning
to see as Mitch outlined, mega mergers within the industry with the acquirers being Coinbase and
Ripple and Stripe and Robinhood and Kraken and so on. We're hoping that 2026 is a year when
traditional finance realizes it needs to buy capability, because it can't build everything
in-house that it needs. And they're frankly too far behind where they need to be. So combining
all of that together, we think there's a substantial risk that the capital markets will close down
sometime in 2026, because they always do. We think the DSPAC mergers will become more interesting
to blockchain leading companies that want to be public. We're hopeful that M&A will continue
very strongly in our industry, and that will allow some leading companies to become real
competitors to the world's largest financial institutions. And then capital availability,
there's an awful lot of capital that needs to be deployed towards technology
and is still sealed up in asset classes from the past. So we're not actually worrying about
capital availability. I think the world now understands that our innovations and technologies
deserve to be funded. So we think a lot of capital will flow into our industry, but the exact mechanisms
may be different than those of the past. That's really interesting. I think maybe just to build
a little bit on what you said on the M&A front, it is still surprising to me that you see some of
the world's largest asset managers having not entered this space even. And you'd have to think
that they will have to enter inorganically in some of these categories. I think the BlackRock
Bitcoin ETF is their most profitable product right now. And then you have State Street Global
Advisors isn't doing anything. It's a weird market in that way. Absolutely. And we've seen it before,
so for those of us old enough to remember in the 90s, the financial industry thought the internet
was crap and they didn't need to have online access, online banking, and so on and so on.
We saw the beginnings of the Ameritraids and the E-Trades and so on begin to get traction.
A few people like Bank America and Wells Fargo launched online banking in America.
And then suddenly all of the big players woke up one night and realized we don't have it and we
need it and customers want it. And as you said, you can't then hire a few people and set out on
a journey. If you're an established player, that's a two-year exercise. So they did start
making acquisitions and we saw a flurry of acquisitions and the assets were scarce. That's
the other thing you need to remember, which is there's a lot more banks than there are blockchain,
crypto, custody companies. And there's a lot more asset managers than there are high quality
digital exchanges and marketplaces for assets. So if that lights up next year, everything's
an auction and scarce assets should start going for high prices. And I think that there can't be
a board of an established bank, payment company, or asset management company that isn't going into
the Christmas break with that on their minds. Have we left it too late? How do we really get
accelerated? How do we avoid FISA? Just to use an example, FISA's share price just dropped by half
because the world suddenly woke up to the reality that every product and service they're bringing
to market may not have guaranteed growth in the terminal value. 75% of the value of FISA was in
the terminal value and that just collapsed when people realized that nothing is guaranteed for
traditional financial companies. And I think every bank is confronted by the same issue.
Today's market value relies upon a terminal value that has embedded in an assumption that the products
and services they currently have and the distribution approaches they currently use
are going to carry on growing and almost certainly they're going to be made obsolete.
Such a good point on the scarcity. I mean, you look at the MPC custody market,
you better buy one of those quick if you want to be in that game. You look at things like
travel rule compliance, there's maybe one or two companies that do that right now.
You look at trade execution, there's one or two that matter. So it's such a good point.
I think that there'll be a game of musical chairs here and some of the traditional finance firms
may be left out. I know we're going a little long on this theme, but believe me, Coinbase,
Kraken, Ripple, Robinhood, they know this too. So the acquisitions you're watching them make
are not non-strategic, they're highly strategic. It's like each one of those
blockchain leading companies has mapped out what the future looks like, what are all the
capabilities that are needed, and they're themselves acquiring the things they're missing.
So if you're a traditional finance company, if you don't get going in 2026, I think you're a seller,
not a buyer. Exactly. Mitch, maybe moving the conversation back to the regulatory,
how are you thinking about that for 2026? So again, 25 could not have been a better year,
but looking into 2026, I think it could be even more consequential. And we love your opinion here
as well, Matt, but the way I see it is that right now, much of the crypto space, we effectively
operate in a gray area. We don't know 100% whether these are legal businesses. I think we can just
say that with the current administration, we're clear that they're legal businesses,
but a new election could bring a new round of appointees to these top institutions and things
could flip. And the one exception to that is now stablecoins, where we have this law that sets it
in stone. So it doesn't matter who's in the White House, who comes in these agencies. We have a
sort of broadly accepted legal definition, but the rest of the market remains to be seen what
happens in terms of actual laws. So that's why for me, the single most important thing I'm watching
from the regulatory side is the market structure bill. It's called the Clarity Act in the House.
It already passed in the House. Now it's going through the Senate. We're going to have some sort
of ability to bring these two laws together, but effectively, this bill is going to outline who
governs the spot market, whether it's the SEC or the CFTC, and effectively, whether or not
certain tokens or securities are not. So if we can get a bill through Congress, a market structure
bill, and signed into law, our industry will be in a very defensible place that should be able to
withstand whoever is in the White House. Now the bad news is that it's a midterms year. So the closer
we get to the midterms and the more the Trump family does with crypto, just a little aside,
the more political this issue could get. And I am a little worried that if we don't get something
done in Q1 before in sort of full-fledged political warfare ahead of the midterms that we might not
get anything done. The only counter to that is that stand with crypto, the crypto super PAC,
continues to raise hundreds of millions of dollars and likely will be just as formidable in the
midterms as it was in 2024. But I think it's critically important that for our industry,
we get some market structure bill done so that it doesn't really matter who comes into these
agencies in the future, because as we know in our system, the shoe always is on the other foot at
some point. I think market structure is hugely important. On the two dimensions you talked about,
for the protocols, just give them clarity on how to launch a layer one, layer two protocol.
And then on the security token market, I think that's just a new market creation story.
So ideally, we get it. I guess the question is, if we don't get it, if it stalls out here and
Atkins comes in and does rulemaking, I'm actually pretty optimistic that that specific rulemaking
would be really hard to roll back. I mean, usually when you have SEC coming out with rules,
it's looking at an existing market structure and it's putting more bells and whistles on it.
You rarely see rules that just shut down pockets of the industry. So it would be hard to see Gensler
2.0 coming in and telling Apollo and Fidelity and BlackRock, hey, I know you launched these
tokenized products, but shut them all down tomorrow. I think you'd have a lot of pushback
on something like that. So the consolation prize here might actually be fine, but I agree with
you that we should get a bill done. Can I just add to this? I want to take a different view of this
question because I actually think that governments don't drive innovation and rules and regulations
whilst valuable do not create, in most cases, powerful products and services that customers
want to use. The biggest single driver of change is the latter. It's that someone comes up with
something that people really, really want. And then years in some cases later, we figure out
what new rules and regulations we need to put in place. And the reason why I say that in this
discussion is because I think the genie is out of the box now. I think that the digital natives
are now 55 or so percent of the US and they want these products and services that can be delivered
in real time at no cost to their mobile devices. Every year, just to put it into context, every
year between 1.5 and 2% of the voting population in America is either new or leaves the system.
So we get new 1.5 to 2% per year voters. And then, of course, we get about the same number of people
passing away. The new voters are all young. The new voters all want this. So if you go in a four-year
cycle, you're talking about 6% to 8% more people that want what we're talking about and that swings
the entire election. So I think both from a consumer user perspective, we already talked about we're
on the power curve of opening up digital wallets, using stable coins, tokenizing assets. And then,
from a voting perspective, we're on a power curve of politicians can't ignore the reality that their
voters want this. And I don't see either one of those things being resisted. So whilst we may never
get a market structure bill, that's not going to stop these innovations coming to market. I really
believe that. And Matt, I would say, just to use the internet as an example, we're 40 years in, 40
years. And we still do not have global perspective on fundamental questions like privacy, the right
to be forgotten, copyright infringement, and how to handle it, and many other issues. So I know you
want a market structure bill straight away. I'm actually pretty comfortable right now living
with regulatory uncertainty, because I think the users and the citizens are not going to
stand for this industry being closed down again. That's a really interesting perspective. And
I would feel a lot better living in that world if we didn't have a senator in Massachusetts who is
just trying to shut us down. But I take the point. I think it's a good one to look at historical
analogies. Matthew, maybe staying with you. And I think this is your final key theme to watch.
Are you seeing a convergence with other technologies here?
So everything we just spoke about was very blockchain and crypto focused. So for 2026,
we just said fundamental growth is going in the right direction, tokenization and stable coins
are eating the financial stack, public market boom may be jeopardized, but there's still a lot
of good things happening. And in Washington, we do have concerns about getting everything done
before the midterms. But this last one is the one that we're most excited about. We think that
2026 will be a year in which a variety of innovations begin to converge in ways that will
kick off the next great cycle of startup and innovation funding. And I want to get a bit
more specific here. But for those of us like you, Matt, who have been in blockchain for
10 years and more, we were constantly berated by the question, well, apart from stable coins,
what are the use cases? And we'd always argue back, well, hang on a second, you can't say apart
from stable coins, because every financial transaction requires a way to settle it. And
digital monies is huge. And we've only just begun to scrape the surface. So don't dismiss that one.
That one's a huge one as our digital commodities and digital securities too. But what we're now
beginning to see is the convergence of themes that we've been talking about for decades.
One of them is blockchain and the movement of value over the Internet. Of course, the second
one is AI and advanced intelligence and computing. The third is the Internet of Things and connecting
devices together into ways where they actually transact device to device and increasingly
intelligence to intelligence. And then there's the whole decentralization theme and the notion
of the distribution of the creation of products and services and the use of products and services
on a global scale with or without centralized intermediaries. And we see all of those things
converging. So when we talk to blockchain entrepreneurs, they're no longer blockchain
entrepreneurs. They are software engineers working at the intersection of all of the
convergence of these things. And I don't think we're seeing too many good blockchain engineers
who aren't also thinking about how to leverage AI and whether or not to create micro payment
platforms for device to device interaction or whatever. I think that the biggest single
breakthroughs that we'll get back next year will be convergence plays. They won't be one thing or
the other thing. There'll be a mash up of many things. And if I was an entrepreneur listening
to today's webinar, I would be going away and taking that to heart. In fact, Sam Altman said
an interesting thing very recently said, if I was a venture capitalist, I would not be
backing any AI application companies. I'd be backing whatever's going to come next.
I think this is what's coming next. It is the mashing up of advanced software based innovations
into new year two, four unimagined solutions that we will be using for decades to come. And I'm
very, very excited by 2026 being a year where we'll begin to see some real offerings of that nature.
I think that's spot on. I think the infrastructure has been laid here over the past
five, six, seven, 10 years even. And now you can actually build some of these things. So I think
that's a spot on prediction. Well, guys, this has been awesome, really powerful stuff. And
it was an exciting 2025. Hopefully 2026, we continue with the trend. Where can we send
people to learn more about the firm and maybe get in touch? People can head to our website,
fitthera.com and look at any of our products or funds. We also put out webinars and newsletters
that are on there. Or if you're interested in talking to Matthew or me, feel free to email us
at IR at fitthera.com. Amazing. Well, thanks so much for joining us today, guys. Looking forward
to doing this again next year. Thanks, Matt. Thank you, Matt. And just to remind everyone,
we're the biggest fans of Castle Island. I appreciate it. We love the partnership.
Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink with Castle Island.
To learn more about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. And to listen to all of our podcast
episodes, please visit castleisland.vc.com or just click on the tab on our website. Thanks for listening.